#### Contact

drzmueller@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-zach-mueller-dnp-rn-nea-bc-a3931112b (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Management Leadership Strategic Planning

### Languages

Spanish English

Certifications
NEA-BC

# Dr. Zach Mueller, DNP, RN, NEA-BC

Division Chief Nursing Executive at Medical City Healthcare (Formerly HCA North Texas)

Dallas, Texas

## Summary

Experienced Nursing and Healthcare Executive with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Management, Customer Service, Business Development, Strategic Planning, and Healthcare. Strong healthcare services professional with a BS, MS (CNS: Acute & Critical Care w/ emphasis on Leadership & Management), ND, DNP focused in Nursing from The University of Colorado College of Nursing.

### Experience

Medical City Healthcare (Formerly HCA North Texas) Division Chief Nursing Executive June 2017 - Present (3 years 1 month)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

As a senior leader for one of the largest divisions in HCA, the nation's largest provider of healthcare services, I am responsible for patient care at 17 hospitals that comprise over 14,000 employees. My chief areas of responsibility include ensuring an exceptional patient experience with the highest clinical quality for our community, investing in and retaining nurses, and nurturing an outstanding professional practice environment.

HCA - Medical City Dallas Hospital SVP & Chief Nursing Executive January 2011 - Present (9 years 6 months)

The Medical Center of Aurora/Centennial Medical Plaza Associate CNO May 2004 - January 2011 (6 years 9 months) Aurora, Colorado

## Education

The University of Colorado College of Nursing
BS, MS (CNS: Acute & Critical Care w/ emphasis on Leadership &
Management), ND, DNP, Nursing · (2001 - 2006)

University of Colorado Boulder Bachelor's Degree, Spanish Language and Literature